If you're a fulfillment by Amazon, FBA Seller, the Inventory Defect and Reimbursement IDR Portal
can help streamline how you manage inventory-related defects, damages, and losses.
The Portal consolidates inventory health data from multiple reports into a single dashboard, making
it easier to track inventory problems and gather information needed to file reimbursement claims.
Additionally, it  automatically applies FBA reimbursement policy checks, saving you the time of
manually researching
reimbursable opportunities.
To access the IDR Portal in Seller Central, open the main menu, hover
over Inventory, and select FBA Inventory.
From the FBA Inventory Dashboard, click the Inventory
drop-down, and select Inventory Defect and Reimbursement.
The IDR Overview page displays
a summary of your total affected units and their defect status, featuring a trend chart that can
help you track defect patterns
over time.
These trends can help you investigate common issues that may need to be addressed for improvement.
For example, if you notice a high number of warehouse damage defects for a particular SKU, you might
want to evaluate your product
packaging, or consider additional protective materials to reduce future damages.
Defects in the IDR Portal are organized
into three main tabs, eligible for claim, in progress, and resolved.
You can customize your views using filters to focus on a
specific date range, search for products by SKU, asin, or FNSKU, and sort by defects that occurred
within the
warehouse or during the customer return process.
Each tab also contains a bar chart that visually organizes defect types by
volume, helping you identify your most frequent issues.
You can also select from a drop-down menu to filter and view affected
units within specific defect types.
On the eligible for claim tab, you'll find a list of Inventory Defects that qualify for
reimbursement.
The In Progress tab displays defects currently under Amazon's Review.
The Resolved tab provides a
comprehensive view of defects that have been addressed, detailing the reasoning behind Amazon's
resolution decision.
The Resolution Distribution Pie Chart categorizes outcomes as reimbursed, reconciled, or ineligible.
If you disagree
with a resolution, you can submit a case with seller support, including the Product Defect Information
and a
Detailed Explanation.
We encourage you to leverage the IDR Portal regularly to refine your inventory management
strategies.
For more information, visit the Inventory Defect and Reimbursement IDR Portal Help page in Seller
Central.